<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.gooseberrydevelopment.pinepods</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-only</project_license>

  <name>Pinepods</name>
  <summary>A complete, self-hosted podcast management system</summary>

  <developer id="com.gooseberrydevelopment">
    <name>Gooseberry Development</name>
  </developer>

  <description>
    <p>
      PinePods is a Rust based podcast management system that manages podcasts with multi-user support and relies on a central database with clients to connect to it. It's browser based and your podcasts and settings follow you from device to device due to everything being stored on the server. You can subscribe to podcasts and even hosts for podcasts with the help of the PodPeopleDB. It works on mobile devices and can also sync with a Nextcloud server or gpodder compatible sync server so you can use external apps like Antennapod as well! NOTE: This is the client edition of Pinepods. You must have a server to connect to in order to use this app.
    </p>
    <p>
      Instructions for setting up your own self-hosted server can be found on the main repo
    </p>
  </description>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">com.gooseberrydevelopment.pinepods.desktop</launchable>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/madeofpendletonwool/PinePods/3c84f982bc3d320e2d4ebe6ce2788f5fd656f7b5/images/screenshots/homethemed.png</image>
      <caption>Main interface of Pinepods</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/madeofpendletonwool/PinePods</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/madeofpendletonwool/PinePods/issues</url>
  <url type="donation">https://github.com/sponsors/madeofpendletonwool</url>

  <releases>
    <release version="0.7.6" date="2025-03-23">
      <description>
        <p>I'm excited to announce PinePods 0.7.6, fully showing the power of the new notification system, things like episode downloads will now display percentages as they download in a brand new alert component that's been added. A worker system for background tasks that can be easily monitored on a per user basis so we can now get status of tasks as they execute was added back in version 0.7.4. Now we're starting to see what can be done with it. At this point I am confident Pinepods is the ultimate podcast archival tool. In the near future I will continue to migrate tasks over to this new system which will allow for even greater visibility into exactly what the server is doing. Think monitoring status of Nextcloud sync tasks etc.

In addition this update further improves some findings after the previous 0.7.4 update as it was a big one!</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
  <requires>
    <display_length compare="ge">360</display_length>
  </requires>
  <recommends>
    <display_length compare="ge">548</display_length>
  </recommends>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />
</component>
